有些事一旦开始
When something begins,
没人知道将如何结束
You generally have no idea how it's going to end.
计划卖掉的房子变成了温馨的家
The house you were going to sell becomes your home.
被迫收容的室友却成了至亲的家人
The roommates you were forced to take in become your family.
而本打算当过眼云烟一样对待的一夜情
And the one-night stand you were determined to forget
却成了携手终生的挚爱
Becomes the love of your life.
-你醒了多久  -根本就没睡
- Hey. How long have you been up?  - All night.
我绞尽脑汁
I was trying to figure out
想怎样取出伊兹脑里的肿瘤
how to get the tumor out of Izzie's brain.
-你笑什么  -我想到办法了
- Why are you smiling?  - 'cause I figured out how to do it.
等伊兹治愈  我们就能一起去巴哈马
Once Izzie's in the clear, we're gonna go to the Bahamas
举行一场海滩婚礼
And have our wedding on the beach.
只有你和我出席
The one and only beach club...
你可以在婚礼上喝酒
You can actually have drinks during the ceremony.
你确定自己可以下床走动吗
Are you sure you're okay to be up and around?
当然了  总有感觉好的时候
Yes. I have good days and bad days.
再说  我可不想把蜜月荒废在病床上
Plus, I don't want to spend our entire honeymoon in a hospital bed.
这才不是我们的蜜月
This is not our honeymoon.
这绝对是我们的蜜月
It totally is.
好了  我带你去见见我的朋友
Come on. I want you to meet my friends.
你哪个朋友是我不认识的
I know all your friends.
你认识的全是医生朋友  可我现在是病人
You know all my doctor friends. I'm a patient now.
你要认识我的病友们
You're gonna meet my patient friends,
他们一定会喜欢我的新老公
And they're gonna love my new husband.
-别这么大惊小怪的  -才没呢
- Don't make a big deal.  - I'm not gonna make a big deal.
我嫁人了各位
I'm a bride.
伊兹  拜托了  我会给她买个真钻戒的
Iz, come on. I'm getting her a real one.
我就喜欢这个
I love this one,
在我心里就是真的
And that makes it a real one.
注意了各位  他是阿历克斯  我的新婚丈夫
Okay, everybody, this is Alex, my husband.
老公  这几位依次是奥斯汀  斯塔
Husband, this is Austin Star
梅格  米盖尔  艾莉森
Meg Miguel and Alison.
你能转身让我们看看你的臀部吗
Can you turn him around so we can see the butt?
照做  阿历克斯
Yes. Alex?
你逗我玩呢吧
What, are you kidding me?
天啊  这家伙伤得真严重啊
No. Oh, a big trauma just came in. That's...
-标准小翘臀  -可不是嘛
-  That's quality booty   - Right?
-伊兹恭喜你  -谢了
- Congratulations, Izzie.  - Thank you.
那个
So, uh...
我今早和心理医生聊得很好
I had a good session with my shrink this morning.
你和她谈你妈妈了吗
Did you talk to her about your mom?
你去见过你妈妈了吗
I mean, have you seen your mom yet?
她就住在几公里外
'cause she lives, like, you know, a few miles away,
她还以为你在伊拉克呢
And she thinks you're still in Iraq.
我...我有打算去见她
Yeah, I...I'm planning to see her.
什么时候去
When?
亨特医生  我今天不在外伤科当班
Dr. Hunt... I'm not on trauma today?
欧麦利  跟我走
Follow me, O'malley.
洛厄尔中尉  我是亨特医生
Lieutenant Lowell, I'm Dr. Hunt.
我们在电话里谈过
We spoke on the phone.
亨特少校  终于见到你了
Major Hunt, it's good to finally meet you.
我的长官和我讲了很多你的事情
My C.O. Has told me a lot about you.
史蒂夫·梅森说什么你都别信
Ah, you shouldn't believe anything Steve Mason tells you.
这位是欧麦利医生  你见过托瑞斯医生了
This is Dr. O'malley, and you've already met Dr. Torres.
我正在看查理的术前扫描
I'm looking at Charlie's post-op scans,
但没发现他腿上有任何的功能性病症
but I'm not finding anything functionally wrong with the leg.
但我既不能走也不能跑  就连动一下
Except that I can't walk or run or move really
都巨疼无比
Without serious pain.
我试了很多治疗方式  药物  理疗
I've tried everything... medications, physical therapy.
都不起作用
Nothing works.
可能是神经损伤
Which could indicate nerve damage.
或是慢性疼痛综合征
Or a chronic pain syndrome.
我们可以研究下止痛治疗
And we can definitely look into pain management procedures,
但是提到手术  我恐怕就无能为力了
But surgically, I'm afraid, uh, there's nothing I can do.
实际上  有个办法
Actually there is.
可以截肢
You could cut it off.
你可以截掉这条腿
You can cut it off
然后给我安装假肢
and replace it with a prosthetic leg
那我就可以回到伊拉克  那需要我
So I can get back to Iraq where I'm needed.
你知道他是来截肢的吗
Did you know that's why he was here?
不知道  但这要求很过分吗
No, but is it such an unreasonable request?
过分  切除可用的肢体  那是电锯杀人狂
Unreasonable? Cutting off a viable limb is dismemberment.
那孩子19岁就当上中尉了
That kid made lieutenant at 19.
他打算把自己一生都奉献给军队
He was planning on spending the rest of his life In the military.
他们还打算要一个瘸腿士兵吗
They gonna take him back with one leg?
很多膝下截肢的士兵
There have been several lower-leg amputees
都能带着假肢回到军队继续服役
Who've returned to active duty with prosthetics.
都是主动要求截肢吗
Voluntary amputees?
也许吧  我不知道
Maybe. I don't know.
你难道要我打发这孩子走吗
Are you saying I have to turn this kid away?
他的长官信任我  才送他来的
His C.O. Sent him here because he trusts me.
我们可以再做一组扫描
We could get another set of scans
-尝试硬膜检查  -托瑞斯医生
- and then try an epidural for the pain.  - Dr. Torres?
行  做一个核磁共振再进行硬膜检查
Fine. Do an M.R.I. And an epidural.
我会研究扫描结果
I'll take a look at the scans,
如果腿是健康的  我说什么也不截肢
But if the leg is healthy, I'm not cutting it off.
-贝利医生  今天忙吗  -不一定
- Dr. Bailey, are you busy today?  - That depends.
看你是不是接收了绝症儿童
You got any more dying children you want me to become
要我在他们临终前与他们亲密接触
Overly attached to before they expire?
没有  是个8岁的成神经细胞瘤患者
No. I have an 8-year-old neuroblastoma patient,
我的第六感告诉我  他肯定能活下来
And he's gonna live. I can feel it in my bones.
你和我一起手术  享受治病救人的快乐
So scrub in with me and see the joy.
贝利医生
Um, Dr. Bailey.
能借用你一会吗
May I borrow you?
谁是圣诞老人
Who is Santa Claus?
一个住在北极的白老头
An old white man who lives at the north pole
总是不合时宜地跑到别人家里
And enters people's homes inappropriately.
你说错了
No.
我才是圣诞老人
I'm Santa Claus.
所有系统准备就绪
All systems ready.
天啊  你该不会
Oh, no, you did not!
是的  没错
Oh, yes, I did.
达芬奇机器人高清手术系统
The Da Vinci Si HD Surgical System
你不会是在我正准备
Tell me you didn't wait till I had all
离开普外科时  才买了这套达芬奇
but left the general surgery program to buy us a Da Vinci!
要不要试驾一下
Care to take it out for a spin?
圣诞老人
Santa.
我一直在想
Hey, I was thinking, you know,
德里克和梅瑞狄斯就要结婚了
With, uh, Derek and Meredith getting married, they, uh,
也许他们不愿我们住在阁楼里了
Probably don't want us hanging out in the attic much longer.
所以我想  要不要找一套公寓
So I was thinking I'd start looking for a condo.
太棒了
Perfect,
你终于有自己的房子了
then you'd finally have a place of your own.
其实  我是想也许  你能
Actually, I was, you know, thinking maybe you'd, uh,
-你过来和我一起  -太好了
- You'd come with me. - Absolutely.
不  我是说  我一定会去看看
No, I-I... I would love to see it.
真为你开心
I'm so happy for you.
你听到多少
How much of that did you hear?
是你打算约人家同居呢
You mean the part where you asked her to move in with you,
还是人家彻底拒绝了你
Or the part where she shot you down?
我都听全了
I was here for both.
顺便说说
By the way,
你和莱西同居还为时过早
It's just way too early for you to be moving in with Lexie.
你没必要学我的样
You don't have to do everything I do.
和你完全没关系
This is not about you.
我对未来有自己的考量  人生苦短
I have my own future to think about. Life is short.
斯蒂文斯怎么样了
Look at what's going on with Stevens.
你不用担心她
Don't worry about Stevens.
我自有办法
I got a plan.
你要摘除她的海马体
You want to remove her hippocampus?
其中一个而已  常用于癫痫病人的治疗
One of them. It's a common procedure for seizure patients.
摘除海马体会伤及记忆及语言功能
Removing her hippocampus could compromise her memory, her speech.
她就无法继续进行药物治疗了
She wouldn't be able to practice medicine anymore.
此类手术我已做过数百例了
I have performed this surgery hundreds of times.
-针对癌症病人吗  -不是  但
- On cancer patients?  - No, but it's...
如果你做手术  我可能会失去记忆
If you do the surgery, I could lose my memory?
有这可能  但可能性极小
It's unlikely, but it's possible.
如果不做手术呢
And if you don't do the surgery?
我们可以用白介素2缩小肿瘤
We could shrink the tumor with I.L.-2.
前提是我没有被癌症先杀死
If the tumor doesn't kill me first.
为什么要冒险
Why take the chance?
你为什么不先进行瓦达测试
Have you even done a Wada test
看看记忆会不会因此受到影响
to see how her memory would be affected?
让大脑进入休眠
Putting her brain to sleep
让她记忆一张张闪过的卡片
and asking her to remember a bunch of flash cards
并不能提供准确的术后结果
is not an accurate assessment of the post-surgical outcome.
但起码告诉我们  术后能否正常生活
But it would tell us whether or not she could function afterwards,
-作为她的主治医生  -我做就是了
- and as Dr. Stevens' primary physician... - Fine, I'll do it.
根本就没必要
It's unnecessary...
是手术没意义  肿瘤已引发病症
The surgery is unnecessary. The tumor's already symptomatic.
她出现幻觉
She's having hallucinations.
戒指真漂亮
That's a nice ring.
看来阿历克斯大出血了
Alex outdid himself.
我们的孩子会很漂亮  你说是不
We're gonna have beautiful kids, Don't you think?
四个孩子算多吗
Is four too many?
四个正好
Four is perfect.
最好是两个男孩  两个女孩
Ideally, it would be two boys and two girls...
其中一个会是假小子
One of which would definitely be a tomboy.
我觉得我该和他们亲密些
And I was thinking I should have them pretty close together,
虽然听起来很傻
Though that might be stupid.
心动不如行动
Why wait?
说得对
Exactly.
假如我不能继续接受药物治疗
That way, If I'm not able to practice medicine anymore...
你不想的
You won't want to.
你这么认为
You don't think?
难道不是吗
Do you?
我问你呢
I'm asking you.
为啥我说什么你都不反对
Why do you keep agreeing with everything I say?
因为我就是你  是你的肿瘤
Because I am you. I'm your tumor.
你在和自己讲话
You're... talking to yourself.
对啊
Right.
至少在手术前是如此
At least until you have surgery,
如果你要做手术的话
If you have surgery.
你打算做手术吗
Are you gonna have surgery?
德里克若切除肿瘤  我就可能失去记忆
If Derek cuts the tumor out, I could lose my memory,
但若不做手术  我就会死
And if he doesn't, I could die.
我不知道怎么办
I don't know what to do.
阿历克斯告诉我怎么办
Alex, tell me what to do.
-伊兹  我不能告诉你  -你当然可以
- Iz, I can't tell you what to do.  - Of course you can.
你是我老公  老公的职责啊
You're my husband. That's what husbands do.
他们不都是跺着脚  告诉老婆该怎么做的嘛
They stomp around telling their wives what to do.
这是你的职责啊
It's your job.
不对  我的职责是支持你一切的决定
No, my job is to support whatever you want to do.
可我根本不知道怎么决定
I don't know what I want to do.
所以才问你的
That's why I'm asking you.
好吧  我有个主意
Okay, I have an idea.
我们投票决定  谁赞同手术
Let's put it to a vote. All in favor of the surgery...
不  我们不投票  没人会去投票
No, we're not voting. No one's...no one's voting.
谁反对
Opposed?
我反对
I'm opposed...
反对投票
To voting.
帮我做个决定吧  拜托了
Just decide for me. Please.
你不用现在决定  仔细想想
You don't have to know right now. Think about it.
我没时间了
I don't have time.
梅森上尉说  你救过他的命
Captain Mason told me that you saved his life
就在战场上  至少救了他四次
At least four times in the field.
还有几次是在食堂里
Yeah, and a couple of times in the canteen,
别告诉他是我说的
But don't tell Mason I told you that.
那  你认为我能回得去
So... you think I'll get to go back?
你确定你想回去吗
Are you sure you want to?
为什么宁愿把腿截了
I mean, why do you want to cut off your leg
也要回到战场
Just to go back to the war?
你有家人吗
Don't you have family?
你是否能体会  虽有家人可他们不了解你
You know what it's like to have family who don't know you,
他们不理解你  甚至不喜欢你
Who don't get you, maybe even don't like you?
是的  我有几个兄弟
Yeah, actually, uh, I have brothers.
我一样  我那一家人
Me too，So there's that family,
和我一起长大的兄弟们
The guys I grew up with,
我们之间毫无共同语言
And we've got nothing in common,
而我在伊拉克的兄弟们
And then there's my guys in Iraq...
才是真正的家人
My real family
无论身陷何处  我们同生共死
Whatever we got into, we were in it together.
但在这  我只能孤身一人
But here, I'm alone. I'm nobody.
我尝试过
And I've tried.
尝试过融入这里的生活
You know, I've tried fitting in here.
过普通人的生活
I've tried being a regular person.
尝试找份工作  但找不到
I've tried getting a job, but there aren't any.
我这辈子有无数梦想
There are a lot of things that I wanted to be in my life,
有许多事想要做
A lot of things I wanted to do,
但都不是在这儿
But none of them's here.
艾莉森·克拉克  她两年前向我求医
This is Alison Clark. She was referred to me two years ago.
转移灶进入了大脑  肝脏及肾脏
Mets in her brain, liver, kidney?
她做了五次手术
She ended up having five surgeries
还接受过广泛性化疗  治疗成功了
And extensive chemo, which worked,
但后来
But then...
是啊  转移灶又复现了
Oh, yeah, the mets came back.
那时起我开始对她进行白介素2疗法
That's when I started her I.L.-2 therapy.
现在
And now...
经过三个月三次治疗后
After three treatments in as many months...
转移灶不见了
The mets are gone?
The mets are gone.
斯蒂文斯医生需要耐心
Dr. Stevens should be patient.
她需要尝试一下此疗法
She should give her therapies a chance.
作为外科医生  我们老想着切割动作
As surgeons, we like to cut,
不过
But...
有时可以另辟蹊径
Sometimes there's a better way.
我来把小肠缩进些
Let me retract that small bowel
好让你看得更清楚
So you'll have better visualization.
说真的  主任
You know what, chief?
-多亏了列奥  你不必这么做了  -列奥
- Thanks to Leo, you don't have to. - Leo?
列奥纳多·达·芬奇
Leonardo... Da Vinci.
这儿  这儿  看着
Here, here, watch this.
看见没
See?
540度腕关节运动
540 degrees of wristed movement.
腹腔镜可做不到
Can't do that with a laparoscope.
开放性手术也不行
Or in open surgery.
感觉很棒吧
Feels pretty good, doesn't it?
贝利医生
Dr. Bailey,
你在模仿光剑的声音吗
Are you making lightsaber noises?
抱歉  主任
Uh, not anymore, sir.
克利夫兰诊所的查利康达医生
You know, Dr. Chalikonda at Cleveland Clinic
正进行肚脐单切口胆囊切除术
Is doing single-incision gall bladder removal through the belly button.
我们下一次也能尝试一下
We could try that on the next one...
如果你愿意的话
If you're up to it.
别逗我了  主任
Don't tease me, sir.
我没逗你
Oh, I'm not.
凭什么让查利康达医生独乐乐
Why should Dr. Chalikonda have all the fun?
真厉害  但花了两年时间才见成效
It's impressive, but it took two years to get these results.
但这两张片子的拍摄间隔仅三个月
Yeah, but these two scans were taken three months apart.
伊兹恐怕没有三个月时间
But Izzie may not have three months.
肿瘤也许三天后就会出血  也许三秒后
That tumor could start bleeding in three days or three seconds.
从何时起你不主张手术了
And since when are you not about cutting?
因为不手术是为病人好
Since it may not be in the best interest of our patient.
难道德里克不是为伊兹好吗
And Derek's not acting in Izzie's best interest?
放射室准备就绪了
They're ready for us in radiology.
听着  伊兹
Okay, Iz,
我将给你看几张
I am going to show you a series...
几张图片  并且要我尽力记住
A series of images that you want me to try to remember
稍后德里克会令我的右脑休眠
Once Derek puts the right side of my brain to sleep.
-来吧  你手上有些什么  -开始
- Hit me. Show me what you got. - Okay.
这是髯狗还是苏格兰狗
Is that a schnauzer or a scottie?
-我需要记得多详细  -是狗就行了
- How specific do I need to be?  - Dog's fine.
波音727或是747
It's either a 727 or a 747.
飞机
Plane.
双层的维多利亚庄园
Ooh, a 2-story victorian mansion.
我们就当它是"房子"
We would also accept the word "house."
髯狗  波音747  庄园
Schnauzer, 747, mansion.
或者说  狗  飞机  房子
Or dog, plane, house.
我要让你的右脑休眠了  准备
I'm gonna put the right hemisphere of your brain to sleep now, okay?
狗  飞机  房子  狗  飞机  房子
Dog, plane, house. Dog, plane, house.
狗  飞机  房子
Dog, plane, house.
狗  飞机  房子  狗  飞机  房子
Dog, plane, house. Dog, plane, house.
狗  飞机  房子
Dog, plane, house.
好了  现在只待那部分大脑停止活动
Okay, now we just wait for the brain activity in that area to stop.
狗  飞机  房子  狗  飞机
Dog, plane, house. Dog, plane...
房
H...
好了  伊兹  告诉我你看见了什么
Okay, Iz. Can you tell me what you saw?
给她看卡片
Show her the cards.
这是什么
Um... what's this?
狗
Dog.
你能说"狗"吗
Can you say dog?
-我叫什么名字  -还是用卡片  梅瑞狄斯
- What's my name?  - Just stick to the cards, Meredith.
梅瑞狄斯
Meredith.
你知道我的名字  你可以说出来的
You know my name. You can say my name.
这正是我的担心所在
This is what I was afraid of.
这样  阿历克斯是谁
Okay, who's Alex?
伊兹  听着  你不用说出来
Iz, okay, you don't have to speak.
只要点点头  表示你知道克莱夫是谁
Just nod your head for me if you know who Alex Karev is.
测试结果显示  记忆受抑制太深
The test impaired your memory to such a degree that
我强烈建议你不要接受手术
I have to strongly recommend you don't have the surgery.
伊兹  测试显示的是手术的最坏结果
Izzie, the test was the worst-case scenario.
不能等同于手术结果
The result has nothing to do with the surgery.
这还无法断定
We don't know that.
但我能断定  不做手术
What I do know is that not operating
不比做手术风险低
Is every bit as risky as the surgery itself,
也许更危险  你自己决定
If not more, but it's up to you.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
他在问你  不是我
I think he's talking to you, not me.
我让你俩单独商量一下
I'll leave you two alone to discuss this.
我跟你出去  我有些问题要问
I'll come with you. I have a couple of questions.
等等  阿历克斯
Wait, Alex.
你好好想想自己想要如何决定
Just think about what you want to do for a second, okay?
我一会儿就回来
I'll be right back.
不要做手术
You are not having this surgery.
别跟我谈医生那套  好吗
I need you to not talk medicine to me, okay?
把我当朋友
Talk to me like I'm your friend,
你早上偷吃他麦片的朋友
Like I'm the guy whose cereal you eat in the morning,
-告诉我该怎么决定  -克莱夫
- And tell me what to do.  - Karev...
拜托  克莱夫  我不能替下决定
Please. Karev, I can't tell you what to do.
就当她是梅瑞狄斯
What if it was Meredith?
你会怎么选择
What would you do if you had to choose
与梅瑞狄斯共渡几个月时光
Between spending a few more months with Meredith
明知她会死去
Knowing she was gonna die...
看着她痛苦  难受
Watching her hurt, watching her sick...
还是用你的余生
Or spending the rest of your life
陪伴一个只是长得像梅瑞狄斯的女人
With someone who looked like Meredith but wasn't her anymore?
她是我一生中最珍贵的宝物
She's the one good thing that ever happened to me,
最最珍贵
The one good thing.
我必须知道该如何决定
So I need to know what to do.
我要你告诉我  如果她是梅瑞狄斯
I need you to tell me... what if it was Meredith?
我会要求她接受手术
I would ask her to have the surgery.
你什么都忘了
You couldn't remember anything.
甚至记不起我的名字
You didn't know my name.
你不认识德里克  不认识阿历克斯
You didn't know who Derek was. You didn't know who Alex was.
你更是忘了如何说话
You couldn't even remember how to speak.
我怎么一点印象也没有
How come I don't remember any of this?
因为肿瘤生长的位置
Because the tumor is sitting right in the middle
正是你的本性所在
Of everything that makes you you.
我当时就站在那儿跟你说话
I was standing there talking to you
就像现在一样
Exactly like I am now,
但你当时不在
Only you weren't there.
那不是你  你消失了
You weren't you. You were gone.
那我该怎么做
So what do I do?
斯万德有个病人
Well, Swender has a patient...
女性  22岁  转移性恶性黑素瘤
Female, 22 years old, metastatic melanoma.
艾莉森·克拉克
Alison Clark?
进过三个月的白介素2疗法
After three months of the I.L.-2,
她的转移灶消失了  全部消失了
Her mets were gone... all of them.
你不能接受手术
You're not having this surgery.
别  我投反对票
Don't do it. That's my vote.
别做手术
Don't have the surgery.
我就没做  我恨死手术了
I didn't. I freaking hate surgery.
可我有幻觉  艾莉森
I'm hallucinating, Alison.
我和死去之人交谈了很久
I have really long conversations with dead people
我还能看到那些...
And I see things that aren't...
比如现在
Like right now, for example,
我确信你头上没有鸟儿在盘旋
I'm pretty certain there aren't birds flying over your head
因为这里是医院  有鸟就荒唐了
Because this is a hospital and that would be weird,
但我确实看到了
But that's what I'm seeing.
我脑内有肿瘤  我真不要让他们切除吗
I have a brain tumor. Am I really not gonna let them cut it out?
我没让他们切除
I didn't let them cut out mine.
怎么说呢
It's like...
某一刻  我是个大学生
Okay, one minute, I'm this college kid,
出游划船  傻得忘记涂防晒霜
Rowing crew and being an idiot and forgetting my sunscreen
却不以为然
and thinking it doesn't matter
因为那就是我
Because I'm me,
我的生活过得好好的
And life has worked out pretty well for me.
可是突然间
And then the next minute,
他们每两周就要对我做手术
They're cutting into my body every other week.
我做了十五次手术
I had 15 surgeries.
后来我说  够了
And then I said, enough.
随它去吧
Forget it.
到了天堂  我照样划船去
I'll row crew in heaven or whatever.
再后来  白介素2起效了
And then the I.L.-2 worked.
真起效了
It worked.
我每三周来一次
I come here every three weeks,
拿我的药就行
I get my medicine,
我脑里再也没有肿瘤了
And... I don't have a brain tumor anymore.
查理  如果我们同意手术
Charlie, if we admit you,
如果我们按你说的做
If we do what you're asking us to do,
你腿上的伤痛
The pain in your leg...
我们无法保证截肢能够治愈
There's no way of knowing if amputation will cure it.
但是有可能
But it might.
-是有可能  -一旦我装上假肢
- Yes, it might. - And once I get the prosthetic, then...
但我得花上数月时间准备
Uh, it will be months before I can even begin
才能替你接上假肢
Fitting you with a prosthetic,
假肢与真腿的感觉完全不同
Which won't feel anything like a new leg, by the way.
只会觉得是一块五磅重的金属  还很疼
It will feel like 5 pounds of metal that hurts and pinches.
-万一军队不要你怎么办  -不会的
- And what if the army says no?  - No, no...
-如果他们不让你归队  -不会的  可能是...
- What if they don't take you back? - They will. Chances are that...
你真愿意冒险吗  查理
You really want to take that chance, Charlie?
你这是在要求切除你的腿
You're asking me to remove one of your limbs.
你以为我不知道吗
Yeah, you think I don't know that?
你以为我愿意砍掉一条腿吗  当然不
You think I want to cut my leg off? Of course not.
我一定要看腿吗  才不
Am I sure about this? No.
但我感觉我正身处地狱之中
The only thing I'm sure about is that I am in hell right now.
这点我确信不疑
That I am sure of.
我失去了一切
I've lost everything...
我曾为之付出的一切  我所在意的一切
Everything I've worked for, everything that I care about...
到头来却必须每日服六次止痛药
And I've traded it in for a 6-times-a-day pain-pill habit
还不起效
that doesn't even work.
别浪费大家的时间来吓唬我了
So don't waste both our times by trying to scare me,
你吓不了我  托瑞斯医生
Because you do not scare me, Dr. Torres.
经历诸多苦难之后  什么都吓不倒我
After everything I've been through, nothing scares me.
到底做不做手术
So are we gonna do this or not?
罗宾斯医生
Dr. Robbins,
贝利医生刚进行了本院
Dr. Bailey just performed Seattle Grace's
首例单切口胆囊切除术
First single-incision gall bladder removal.
真棒
That's cool.
从病人肚脐下刀
Through the patient's belly button.
这下听起来有点恐怖了
And now it's kinda creepy.
不是的  你该去观摩
No, no. You shoulda seen it.
没有伤疤  没有出血
No scars, no bleeding,
比用腹腔镜节省了一半时间
and about half the time it would've taken laparoscopically.
午饭后你想做一例吗
You want to do one after lunch?
我这还有一例结肠手术
I've got another coli.
可以吗
Y-you don't mind?
看来
Oh, well, also,
我下午得一个人当班了
I guess I'm on my own for this afternoon.
我的成神经细胞瘤手术
My neuroblastoma?
别别别  一点儿都别担心
No, no, no, no. Don't worry. You don't have to.
你以后有的是成神经细胞瘤手术的机会
You'll have the rest of your life to do neuroblastomas.
-那好  午饭后见啦  主任  -好
- Well, then I'll see you after lunch, sir. - Okay.
主任
Chief.
什么事  罗宾斯医生
Yes, Dr. Robbins.
主任
Chief...
你有话要说吗
Did you want to tell me something?
我要哭了  我想让你知道
I am going to cry, and I just want you to know
我知道自己要哭了
That I know that it's going to happen,
我希望你别理会
And I just want you to ignore it.
我不是因为着急而哭
And I'm not crying because I'm upset.
只是我生上级的气时  就会哭
It's just what happens when I get mad at people of authority.
你生我的气
You're mad at me?
我是生你的气
I am mad at you.
我哭是因为你是上司  我的上司
And I'm crying because you're the boss, my boss,
也就产生了上司及父亲问题
Which brings up my issues of authority and my dad,
你让我想起了我父亲
Who you kind of remind me of.
不是说你老  而是你令人起敬
Not that you're old, but you command respect.
所有人都尊敬你  我尊敬你
People respect you. I mean, I know I do,
贝利也尊敬你  所以我才生气
And I know Bailey does, which is why I'm mad.
因为这样是不对的  主任
Because it's wrong, sir.
你怎么能利用机器人
It's wrong and mean to use a robot
来引诱贝利医生重投普外科
To lure Dr. Bailey back into general surgery
因为我没有机器人
'cause I don't have a robot.
我只有小孩子
All I have are little kids,
而且  他们远不如机器人有诱惑力
And... they're not as fun as a robot.
他们也不会闪闪发亮  闪现银色光泽
And they're not shiny and...and new and silver
他们肚脐眼里也出不来什么东西
And they don't have things coming out of their belly buttons,
但是  我会争到底的  我会赢的  主任
But... I will fight you, and I will win... sir.
你觉得你能争得过我吗
You think you can fight me and win?
是的
Yes.
祝你好运
Good luck.
因为我有一样你没有的法宝
Because I have something that you don't have.
那就是乐趣
I have joy...
主任
Sir.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们在商讨伊兹的白介素2疗程
Oh, we're just going over, uh, Izzie's I.L.-2 schedule.
是术后疗程吗
Oh, for after the surgery?
我决定不接受手术了
I decided not to have the surgery.
什么
What?
我们还是出去一会儿吧
Uh, maybe we should come back...
-杨医生  -好
- Dr. Yang.  - Yeah.
-你必须手术  -什么
- You're having the surgery.  - What?
-谢博德说这是你最后的机会  -但我决
- Shepherd said this is your last shot. - But I dec...
我是你丈夫
Look, I am your husband,
我说你必须做手术
And I say that you are having the surgery.
你不是说  "这是你的决定"
What happened to, "this is your decision"?
那是因为我以为你会做出正确的选择
That was when I thought you were gonna make the right one.
但你选错了
But you chose wrong,
所以现在你失去了选择权
So now you don't get to make this decision on your own,
因为你嫁给了我
Because you married me.
不再是你一人在冒险了
It's not just your life at stake anymore.
我也在与你一同冒险
It's my life, too, my life with you.
随你跟斯万德怎么说
So you can tell Swender whatever you want,
我要告诉谢博德  我也要告诉你
But I'm telling Shepherd and I'm telling you,
你一定得做手术
You're having the surgery.
她是你朋友没错
She may be your friend,
但并不代表你有权走进房间
But that doesn't give you the right to go in and...
劝她放弃手术  你懂什么
And talk her out of a surgery you know nothing about.
你又不是她的医生  你是斯万德的住院医生
You're not her doctor. You're Swender's resident.
你的所作所为既不恰当  也不专业
What you did is not only inappropriate... It is unprofessional.
-德里克  -你出格了  克里斯蒂娜
- Derek...  - You crossed the line, Cristina.
-而你  -她没有
- And this.  - No, she didn't.
是我
I did.
是我说服伊兹不做手术的
I'm the one who convinced Izzie not to have the surgery.
你该训的是我
I'm the one you should be yelling at right now.
那我就走了
Well, I'm gonna go now.
如果你想道歉的话
Unless you want to apologize to...
算了
Okay.
我妈妈可谓是在我眼前消失的
My mother disappeared right in front of me.
她曾拥有的一切  她的一切过往
Everything she had, everything she was...
她的尊严  记忆
Her dignity, her memory.
到头来  她不再是我妈妈了
In the end, she wasn't even my mother anymore.
伊兹跟你妈妈不同
Izzie is not your mother.
她的大脑病况并非无药可治
She doesn't have an untreatable brain condition.
她只是得了肿瘤  可以治得好
She has a tumor, and it can be treated.
-别受私心影响  梅瑞狄斯  -我没有
- Don't make this personal, Meredith. - I wasn't.
你作为朋友去找伊兹
You went to Izzie as her friend
你还替她做下决定
And you made up her mind for her.
你是我的住院医生
So now as my resident,
我要你回去改变她的想法
you go back there and change it,
那肿瘤会杀了她的
Because this tumor will kill her.
问个小问题  杨医生
Quick consult, Dr. Yang.
你干嘛
What are you doing?
我明白了  我对母亲隐瞒我回来的事实
I've realized the reason I haven't told my mother I'm back
是因为一部分的我还在战场上
Is because part of me is still over there.
我没能履行我对军队的誓言
I made a commitment to the army that I wasn't able to fulfill.
如果我那支小队没有被消灭
If my unit hadn't been destroyed,
我现在还在战场上
I would still be there.
难怪我会半夜失眠
So no wonder I can't sleep at night
无法看着我母亲的眼睛
Or...or look my mother in the eye.
难怪你我的关系无法进展
No wonder you and I... we can't move forward.
我战场上的任务尚未完成
My work there isn't done.
在那之前  这里不属于我
Until it is, I have no business being here.
所以  我决定回去
So... I've decided to go back.
我得走了
I have to go.
-克里斯蒂娜  -怎么
- Cristina, come on.  - What?
你想让我怎么说
I'm sorry. What am I supposed to say?
我需要你的支持
I could use your support.
休想
You don't have it.
托瑞斯医生
Dr. Torres.
欧麦利医生
Dr. O'malley.
没关系  查理
It's okay, Charlie.
-你不必这么做的  -不  有必要
- You don't have to do that. - No, I do,
因为你们都在尽量做好工作
'cause you were both just trying to do your job in there,
而你们的工作就是让人们安全团聚
And your job is to put people back together,
而不是把他们拆散  我理解了
Not take them apart, and I get that.
而且我也明白了即使活着回去
And I know it doesn't make sense to you
却只会伤害别人
That I would want to go back to a place
对你们来说也是没有意义的
Where people get hurt and die, but...
我们存在的意义因为我们也想帮助别人
We're there because we're trying to help people,
救助人们  和你们一样
Save people, same as you.
也是我的工作  我存在的意义
It's my job, who I am, it's...
如有有什么意外发生
If something happened,
然后突然间你不能继续从医
And suddenly you couldn't be a doctor anymore,
如果有人告诉你不能继续的话
If someone told you you couldn't do it anymore,
难道你们不会竭尽一切可能
Wouldn't you want to do everything you could possibly do
重新从医吗
To be a doctor again?
我们结婚甚至不到24小时
We haven't even been married 24 hours yet,
却已经吵了夫妻间的第一架了
And we've already had our first fight.
那是个好现象
That's a good sign.
争吵引向和谐的性生活
Fighting leads to good makeup sex.
你是不是又看见鸟在我的头顶飞翔
Are you watching birds fly around my head again?
我现在看起来绝对像白雪公主吧
Am I, like, totally snow white right now?
我只是不想伤害他
I just don't want to hurt him.
他会理解过来的
He'll come around.
可能会得一段时间  但当肿瘤消失后
It might take a while, but once that tumor disappears,
当你回到工作上  给人们做手术
Once you're back at work, cutting open other people,
他就会理解的
He'll come around.
那个是蜂鸟吗
Is it hummingbirds at least?
我真的很喜欢蜂鸟
I really like hummingbirds.
我们得和伊兹谈谈
We need to go talk to Izzie.
不  我们不能只是因为你未来的老公
No, we are not talking Izzie into having surgery
对你很生气  就去劝说伊兹做手术
Because your future husband is mad at you.
但他有权利生气
But he has a right to be mad
因为我们没有站在医生的立场去劝说
Because we didn't talk Izzie out of the surgery
伊兹不做手术  而只是站在朋友的立场
As her doctors, we did it as her friends.
不  作为医生我们的工作只是提供选择
No, our job as doctors is to present the options,
解答问题
Answer questions
然后让病人来决定他们的治疗过程
And let the patient decide their course of treatment.
那才是我们的工作
That is what we did. Right.
除了我可能也告诉了她的选择有
Except I may have presented her options as,
除非我死了  你不能做这手术
"you're having the surgery over my dead body."
他有权利生气
He has a right to be mad.
糟糕
Oh, crap.
是谁
Who is it?
伊兹  发生了什么事
Izzie? What the... what happened?
我不知道  斯万德在哪
I don't know. Where's Swender?
伊兹  让我来  伊兹  坐下
Izzie, let me take over. Izzie, come sit down.
血管和神经分离了
The vessels and nerves are separated.
皮瓣也好了
Skin flap is done.
再提醒我一遍为什么我这么做
Remind me again why I'm doing this.
请某人再提醒我一遍
Someone please remind me again.
你不知道这孩子会怎么样
You don't know what's gonna happen to this kid,
他可以赢多少战斗  可以拯救多少生命
How many fights he could win, how many lives he could save.
但如果你不这么做的话
If you don't do this,
他将毫无机会
He's never gonna get the chance.
我们不是在伤害他  我们没有
We're not doing harm. We're not hurting him.
我们在拯救他
We are saving him.
我们在按他的要求做
We're doing what he wants.
这就是他所需要的
It's what he wants.
血压还在下降
B.P.'s still dropping.
我们还要多一些血  我们得动作快点
We need more blood. We need to move faster.
我完工了
Okay, I'm done. I'm at the end.
我没看见任何的肠部穿孔
I didn't see any bowel perforation.
-肯定有  再查一遍  -斯万达医生
- It's there somewhere. Run it again. - Dr. Swender...
再查一遍
Run it again.
是的
Yes, ma'am.
白介素2注入得太多了
So much for I.L.-2.
你认为这是我的错吗
You think this is my fault?
你认为是我造成的吗
You think I did this to her?
没有
No, ma'am.
癌症是无法治愈的  杨
There is no cure for cancer, Dr. Yang.
这里只有我们  我们两个人而已
There's only us, the two of us, right here, right now,
和这个众所周知的嚣张病魔斗争
Fighting this thing as aggressively as we know how.
有时那意味着
And sometimes that means
向病人体内注入毒素会杀死癌症
Pumping toxins into the patient to kill the cancer,
同时有时  虽然不常见  但的确
And yes, sometimes, not very often, but sometimes,
那些毒素也会杀了病人
Those toxins kill the patient as well.
但艾利森当初来看我的时候
But Alison had three months to live
有三个月可以活
When she first came to see me,
而我成功地让她活了两年
And I have managed to keep her alive for two years.
所以不管什么时候我都不会放弃她
So I am not about to give up on her
或者是白介素2
Or the I.L.-2 anytime soon,
你也一样不应该放弃
And neither are you.
我当时不是在邀请你来观赏保险套
I wasn't asking you to come see the condo.
我是在邀请你和我一起住
I was asking you to move in with me...
如果那是你所想的话
If that's what you want.
是的
I do.
你这么想吗
You do?
是的  不是立刻
Yeah. Not right away.
-当然不是  一年内吗  -还是十年
- No, of course not. In, like, a year. - Ten years.
-不好意思  刚才说什么  -呃  因为
- I'm sorry, what now? - Oh, um, well, because
我好像还要做六年住院医生
I'll still be a resident for, like, six more years,
然后我想继续锻炼
And...and then I'd want to get my practice up and running.
七年怎么样
So... how about seven?
-五年怎么样  -那我还是住院医生呢
- How about five years? - I'll still be a resident.
那又如何  斯蒂文森和克莱夫也是住院医生
So? Stevens and Karev are residents.
梅瑞狄斯是住院医生  贝利是住院医生
Meredith's a resident, Bailey's a resident...
都结婚了  或者就快了
All married or soon to be,
而且是开心的  或者无论什么
And happily... or whatever.
不好意思  你是在向我
I'm sorry. Are you asking me...
求婚吗
To...to... to marry you?
不
No.
为什么  你愿意吗
Why? Would you?
我们一定得讨论这个吗
Um, should we be having this conversation?
-也许不  -那 好吧
- No, probably not. - No, I... That's... okay.
贝利医生  干得不错今天
Impressive work today, Dr. Bailey.
谢谢  那很有趣
Thank you, sir. It was fun.
对啊  难道不是吗
Yeah, it was, wasn't it?
听起来你们过得很开心啊
Sounds like you guys had a good day.
那个成神经细胞瘤的孩子怎么样了
Oh! How did the, uh, neuroblastoma kid do?
他好极了  手术非常顺利
Oh, he was awesome. The surgery was totally easy,
而且他会痊愈的
And he's gonna make a full recovery.
所以我有些希望你在那里
That's kind of why I wanted you there.
因为你成功救活的孩子
'cause the kids you can save
可以弥补你未能救活的那个
Almost make up for the ones you can't.
我要去监控他的术后情况
Anyways, I'm gonna go monitor him post-op.
然后我会去通知他家人那好消息
And then I'm gonna tell his family the good news.
-你该过去看看  分享下欢乐  -好
- You should stop by, come see the joy. - Okay.
我们不得不切除她的部分肠子
We had to resect part of her bowel.
不幸的是我们没能完成手术
Unfortunately, we weren't able to finish the surgery
因为她的情况很不稳定
Because she was too unstable.
现在她戴上了呼吸器
Right now she's on a ventilator
因为她自己不能呼吸
Because she can't breathe on her own.
但你们会完成那手术的  对吧
But, uh, you're gonna be able to finish the surgery, right?
是的  如果她的情况稳定了
Yes, if she stabilizes.
那时她就可以再次自己呼吸了是吧
And then she'll be able to breathe on her own again?
你女儿的心脏在手术过程中停止了
Your daughter's heart stopped during surgery,
意味着她的大脑没有获得氧气
Which means her brain wasn't getting oxygen.
所以她以后不大可能
So it's unlikely
离开呼吸器了
She'll be able to come off the ventilator.
天哪
Oh, god. Oh, no.
伊兹
Izzie.
你呼叫了我  你还好吗
You paged me. Are you okay?
不好  我不知道该做什么
No. I don't know what to do.
我不知道是否该做这手术
I don't know if I should have the surgery.
我想无论怎样我都会死
I think I'm gonna die either way.
-你得教我该怎么做  你知道该怎么做
- You gotta tell me what to do. - You know what to do.
不  我不知道
No, I don't.
我不知道
I don't.
你知道的
Yes, you do.
你只是太害怕去做
You're just scared to do it.
这种犹豫就是害怕
This back and forth is just fear.
但你已经做了决定了
But you've already made the decision.
你已经决定了
You already made it.
在你决定要同它斗争的时候你就决定了
You made it the second you decided to fight this thing.
回想下  你开始的情景
Just look... where you started.
思考下现在的情景
Look where you are now.
现在你
I mean, now you're this...
无法想象的手术
Incredible surgeon...
还有老师
And teacher.
你是个说干就干的人  记得吗
You're a doer, remember?
导师你很清楚你该做什么
You know exactly what you have to do.
请进
Come in.
我同意做手术
You can do it.
你可以再次在我大脑上手术
You can cut into my brain again.
好吧
Okay.
你能手术  不过
You can do it, but...
我不想最后变成植物人
I don't want to end up a vegetable.
-伊兹  你不会的  -等等  听好
- Izzie, you won't. - No, just listen.
我想要做手术  现在就做
I want the surgery, right now,
但如果出了什么差错
But if something goes wrong,
我也不想最后带上呼吸器
I don't want to end up on a ventilator.
所以我准备签不抢救协议
So I'm signing a D.N.R.
-求你了  -阿历克斯
- Please. - Alex...
你发疯了
Look, you went crazy.
当丹尼签不抢救协议时  你就疯了
When Danny signed that D.N.R., you went crazy.
你想这样吗  想我切断左心室辅助装置
Is that what you want? You want me cutting l-vads?
-不  我  -你想毁了我的工作吗
- No, I... - You want to wreck my career?
因为我会的  我会切断左心室辅助装置
'cause I will. I will freaking cut l-vads before I let you...
停  等等  停一下
Just st...just wait, stop.
你不该放弃  你不该放弃我
You don't get to quit. you don't get to quit on me.
求你了  撕了它吧
Please... tear it up.
不抢救协议  撕了它吧
The D.N.R....tear it up.
当你现在看到这些的时候
Where your eyes are supposed to be right now,
我却看到了白色沙滩
I see white sandy beaches...
而你头后面有一片海洋
And there's an ocean behind your head,
伴随着幽灵漫步
And there are ghosts wandering in and out.
我不能这么活着
I can't live like this.
我不能忍受
And I can't live...
如果手术出了什么差错的话
If something goes wrong in that surgery,
我不想采取任何非常规措施
I don't want any extraordinary measures taken
让我维持生命
To keep me alive.
我不想这样
It's not what I want.
丹尼签不抢救协议时 我都要疯了
I went crazy when Denny signed the D.N.R.
我不明白为什么
Because I didn't understand.
无法理解  现在我懂了
I didn't understand, but now I do.
而且我需要你理解我
And I need you to understand.
我不想让你抓狂
I don't want you to go crazy.
我希望你事业有成
I want you to have a brilliant career,
而且希望我能陪在你身边
And I hope that I get to be here for that,
如果我做不到  我只想就这样离开
But if I can't, I just want to go to the other side.
我不知道另一边是怎样的  但肯定比
I don't know what's there, but it's gotta be better
睡病床和插喉管要舒服得多
Than hospital beds and tubes down my throat,
所以  求求你
So please...
别做傻事
Please don't cut l-vads.
如果真的发生了
If it comes down to it,
让我离开
Just let me go.
现在  亲亲我吧
And right now, kiss me.
拜托  亲亲我吧  闭上你的眼睛
Please, please just kiss me, and close your eyes,
那海滩太让我分神了
Because the beach is so distracting.
我一直以为躺在那的会是我
I always thought it would be me.
以为会像妈妈那样得阿兹海默症
I'd get Alzheimer's like my mother
谁也不记得
And forget everyone.
明天一起去市政厅吧
Let's go to city hall tomorrow.
我不想再过单身的日子了
I don't want to spend another day not being married to you.
好的
Okay.
无论你技术多么高超
It doesn't matter how good you are
多么努力  都无关紧要
or how hard you work.
哪怕可以做所有的研究
You can do all the research,
哪怕精通所有最新的技术
You can master all the latest techniques,
哪怕是最好的医生
Um, you can be the best,
哪怕成为了世上最好的外科医生
You can be the best surgeon in the world...
可还会有病人死去
But your patients are still gonna die.
也许是明天  或是下个月
'cause the next day or the next... month
或是明年  你知道  他们总会死的
Or next year, you know, they're just gonna...
也许出车祸  或是背上长毒痣
Get hit by a car or find a mole on their back
你却无能为力
And there's nothing you can do about it.
我不希望你死
I don't want you to die.
你们没事吧
You okay?
我截掉了一条健康的腿
I cut off a healthy leg.
就这么给截了
I just cut it off.
虽是为了病人好
It was for the patient's own good,
可我仍觉得自己像个屠夫
But still, I feel like a butcher.
我的奇迹就是病人能活着
My miracle case is on life support.
我以为曾成功过  有过奇迹
I thought I had one...One miracle.
有时真讨厌这工作
I hate this job sometimes.
不知道为了什么
I don't know why we do this.
快点  跟我来
Come on. Come with me.
我们来这儿干啥
Okay, what are we doing here?
来看这个
We came to see that.
什么
What?
快乐
The joy.
来之不易啊
It comes around rarely,
太不容易  都将它遗忘了
So rarely we forget it can happen.
做手术就为这个
That's why we do this...
感受快乐
The joy.
我们一辈子都在担心将来
We spend our whole lives worrying about the future...
计划将来
Planning for the future,
试图预测将来
Trying to predict the future...
你跟我一起进去吗
Will you come with me?
以为预测出来就能有所准备
As if figuring it out will somehow cushion the blow.
但将来变幻莫测
But the future is always changing.
又来一个
Got one more.
是个医生  说是今天必须加入
He's a doctor. He says he needs to do it today.
进来
Come in.
将来是心底最深的恐惧
The future is the home of our deepest fears...
欧文
Owen?
妈妈
Hi, mom.
我回家了
I'm home.
也是最不羁的梦
And our wildest hopes.
有一点可以肯定
But one thing is certain...
当将来现身
When it finally reveals itself...
恭喜你  医生
Congratulations, doctor.
欢迎参军
Welcome to the army.
将来
The future...
谢谢
Thank you.
永远出乎意料之外
Is never the way we imagined it.